“/O "/O Better/O to/O be/O No./O 2/O than/O No./O 1/O "/O ,/O that/O 's/O my/O motto/O !/O ”/O 
—/O Hol/O Horse/O Hol/O Horse/O (/O ホル/O ・/O ホース/O ,/O Horu/O Hōsu/O )/O is/O a/O minor/O recurring/O antagonist/O featured/O in/O Stardust/O Crusaders/O ./O 
Hol/O Horse/O is/O a/O mercenary/O wielding/O Emperor/O ,/O a/O Stand/O that/O looks/O like/O and/O functions/O like/O a/O gun/O ./O 
He/O was/O originally/O sent/O by/O DIO/O to/O confront/O the/O Joestar/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION alongside/O J./PERSON Geil/PERSON ./O 
However/O ,/O after/O his/O partner/O is/O defeated/O first/O ,/O he/O makes/O a/O tactical/O retreat/O ,/O returning/O for/O two/O following/O encounters/O ./O 
He/O first/O reappears/O caught/O in/O the/O cross/O fire/O of/O Enya/PERSON the/PERSON Hag/PERSON 's/O own/O attempt/O to/O kill/O the/O Joestar/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION and/O one/O last/O time/O to/O attack/O them/O himself/O alongside/O Boingo/PERSON ,/O finally/O being/O defeated/O in/O the/O latter/O encounter/O ./O 
Hol/O Horse/O also/O appears/O in/O the/O spin/O -/O off/O manga/O "/O Crazy/O Diamond/O 's/O Demonic/O Heartbreak/O "/O as/O a/O main/O character/O ./O 
Hol/O Horse/O and/O Boingo/PERSON ,/O Part/O 1/O (/O ホル/O ·/O ホースとボインゴ/O その1/O ,/O Horu/PERSON Hōsu/PERSON to/O Boingo/ORGANIZATION Sono/ORGANIZATION Ichi/ORGANIZATION )/O is/O the/O thirty/O -/O sixth/O episode/O of/O Stardust/O Crusaders/O ,/O the/O twelfth/O episode/O of/O the/O Egypt/LOCATION Arc/O ,/O and/O the/O sixty/O -/O second/O episode/O of/O the/O JoJo/O 's/O Bizarre/O Adventure/O anime/O ./O 
It/O covers/O Chapter/O 210/O and/O Chapter/O 217/O through/O first/O few/O pages/O of/O Chapter/O 219/O of/O the/O manga/O ./O 
Hol/O Horse/O and/O Boingo/PERSON ,/O Part/O 2/O (/O ホル/O ·/O ホースとボインゴ/O その2/O ,/O Horu/PERSON Hōsu/PERSON to/O Boingo/PERSON Sono/PERSON Ni/O )/O is/O the/O thirty/O -/O seventh/O episode/O of/O Stardust/O Crusaders/O ,/O the/O thirteenth/O episode/O of/O the/O Egypt/LOCATION Arc/O ,/O and/O the/O sixty/O -/O third/O episode/O of/O the/O JoJo/O 's/O Bizarre/O Adventure/O anime/O ./O 
It/O covers/O most/O of/O Chapter/O 219/O through/O Chapter/O 221/O of/O the/O manga/O ./O 
Hol/O Horse/O and/O Boingo/PERSON ,/O Part/O 5/O (/O ホル/O ・/O ホースとボインゴ/O その/O ⑤/O ,/O Horu/PERSON Hōsu/PERSON to/O Boingo/PERSON Sono/PERSON 5/O )/O ,/O originally/O My/O Predictions/O Are/O Never/O Wrong/O (/O 予知にまちがいはなかった/O ,/O Yochi/PERSON ni/O Machigai/ORGANIZATION wa/ORGANIZATION Nakatta/ORGANIZATION )/O in/O the/O WSJ/ORGANIZATION release/O ,/O is/O the/O one/O hundred/O eighth/O chapter/O of/O Stardust/O Crusaders/O and/O the/O two/O hundred/O twenty/O -/O first/O chapter/O of/O the/O JoJo/O 's/O Bizarre/O Adventure/O manga/O ./O 
Hol/O Horse/O and/O Boingo/PERSON (/O ホル/O ・/O ホースとボインゴ/O ,/O Horu/PERSON Hōsu/PERSON to/O Boingo/ORGANIZATION )/O is/O the/O twenty/O -/O third/O story/O arc/O in/O Stardust/O Crusaders/O ./O 
It/O narrates/O Hol/O Horse/O and/O Boingo/PERSON 's/O comical/O attempt/O at/O assassinating/O the/O Joestar/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Hol/O Horse/O and/O Boingo/PERSON ,/O Part/O 4/O (/O ホル/O ・/O ホースとボインゴ/O その/O ④/O ,/O Horu/PERSON Hōsu/PERSON to/O Boingo/PERSON Sono/PERSON 4/O )/O ,/O originally/O Striking/O at/O Exactly/O Midday/O (/O 正午キッカリに命中/O ,/O Shōgo/PERSON Kikkari/PERSON ni/O Meichū/O )/O in/O the/O WSJ/ORGANIZATION release/O ,/O is/O the/O one/O hundred/O seventh/O chapter/O of/O Stardust/O Crusaders/O and/O the/O two/O hundred/O twentieth/O chapter/O of/O the/O JoJo/O 's/O Bizarre/O Adventure/O manga/O ./O 
Hol/O Horse/O and/O Boingo/PERSON ,/O Part/O 3/O (/O ホル/O ・/O ホースとボインゴ/O その/O ③/O ,/O Horu/PERSON Hōsu/PERSON to/O Boingo/PERSON Sono/PERSON 3/O )/O ,/O originally/O My/O Predictions/O Are/O Infallible/O (/O 予知は絶対/O ,/O Yochi/PERSON wa/O Zettai/O )/O in/O the/O WSJ/ORGANIZATION release/O ,/O is/O the/O one/O hundred/O sixth/O chapter/O of/O Stardust/O Crusaders/O and/O the/O two/O hundred/O nineteenth/O chapter/O of/O the/O JoJo/O 's/O Bizarre/O Adventure/O manga/O ./O 
Hol/O Horse/O and/O Boingo/PERSON ,/O Part/O 2/O (/O ホル/O ・/O ホースとボインゴ/O その/O ②/O ,/O Horu/PERSON Hōsu/PERSON to/O Boingo/PERSON Sono/PERSON 2/O )/O ,/O originally/O Sticking/O Your/O Fingers/O in/O a/O Nose/O (/O 鼻に指をつっこめ/O ,/O Hana/PERSON ni/O Yubi/PERSON O/O Tsukkome/O )/O in/O the/O WSJ/ORGANIZATION release/O ,/O is/O the/O one/O hundred/O fifth/O chapter/O of/O Stardust/O Crusaders/O and/O the/O two/O hundred/O eighteenth/O chapter/O of/O the/O JoJo/O 's/O Bizarre/O Adventure/O manga/O ./O 
Hol/O Horse/O and/O Boingo/PERSON ,/O Part/O 1/O (/O ホル/O ・/O ホースとボインゴ/O その/O ①/O ,/O Horu/PERSON Hōsu/PERSON to/O Boingo/PERSON Sono/PERSON 1/O )/O ,/O originally/O A/O New/O Team/O Is/O Formed/O (/O 新コンビ誕生/O ,/O Shin/PERSON Konbi/PERSON Tanjō/PERSON )/O in/O the/O WSJ/ORGANIZATION release/O ,/O is/O the/O one/O hundred/O fourth/O chapter/O of/O Stardust/O Crusaders/O and/O the/O two/O hundred/O seventeenth/O chapter/O of/O the/O JoJo/O 's/O Bizarre/O Adventure/O manga/O ./O 
 