Fawad/PERSON Afzal/PERSON Khan/PERSON (/O born/O 29/O November/O 1981/O )/O is/O a/O Pakistani/O actor/O ,/O producer/O ,/O screenwriter/O ,/O songwriter/O and/O singer/O known/O for/O his/O work/O in/O films/O and/O television/O ./O [/O 2/O ]/O Khan/PERSON is/O a/O recipient/O of/O several/O accolades/O ,/O including/O a/O Filmfare/O Award/O ,/O two/O Lux/O Style/O Awards/O ,/O and/O six/O Hum/O Awards/O ./O Khan/PERSON began/O his/O acting/O career/O on/O the/O television/O sitcom/O ,/O Jutt/PERSON and/O Bond/PERSON ./O He/O formed/O an/O alternative/O rock/O band/O ,/O Entity/ORGANIZATION Paradigm/ORGANIZATION ,/O with/O the/O show/O 's/O co-stars/O and/O began/O his/O music/O career/O as/O its/O lead/O singer/O ./O The/O band/O appeared/O on/O the/O finale/O of/O Pepsi/ORGANIZATION Battle/O of/O the/O Bands/O in/O 2002/O and/O Khan/PERSON became/O known/O for/O its/O 2003/O debut/O album/O ,/O Irtiqa/O ./O After/O about/O 250/O performances/O ,/O he/O left/O the/O band/O to/O pursue/O a/O film/O career/O ./O Khan/PERSON made/O his/O film/O debut/O with/O a/O supporting/O role/O in/O the/O social/O drama/O ,/O Khuda/PERSON Kay/PERSON Liye/PERSON (/O 2007/O )/O ,/O one/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O highest/O -/O grossing/O films/O ./O He/O had/O his/O first/O success/O in/O television/O period/O drama/O ,/O Dastaan/O (/O 2010/O )/O ,/O for/O which/O he/O received/O the/O Best/O Male/O Actor/O Award/O at/O the/O Pakistan/LOCATION Media/O Awards/O ./O Khan/PERSON played/O a/O lead/O role/O in/O the/O Pakistani/O television/O serial/O Humsafar/O (/O 2011/O )/O ,/O and/O appeared/O in/O Sultana/PERSON Siddiqui/PERSON 's/O family/O drama/O Zindagi/PERSON Gulzar/PERSON Hai/PERSON (/O 2012/O )/O ./O For/O both/O performances/O ,/O he/O received/O the/O Lux/O Style/O Award/O for/O Best/O Actor/O ./O Khan/PERSON made/O his/O Bollywood/O debut/O with/O the/O romantic/O comedy/O ,/O Khoobsurat/O (/O 2014/O )/O ,/O for/O which/O he/O received/O the/O Filmfare/O Award/O for/O Best/O Male/O Debut/O ./O He/O further/O received/O critical/O praise/O for/O starring/O in/O the/O family/O drama/O Kapoor/ORGANIZATION &/O Sons/ORGANIZATION (/O 2016/O )/O ,/O which/O earned/O him/O a/O nomination/O for/O the/O Filmfare/O Award/O for/O Best/O Supporting/O Actor/O ./O Following/O a/O brief/O hiatus/O ,/O Khan/PERSON made/O a/O comeback/O with/O his/O Marvel/O Cinematic/O Universe/O debut/O in/O the/O miniseries/O Ms./O Marvel/O (/O 2022/O )/O as/O Hassan/PERSON ./O His/O action/O -/O adventure/O film/O The/O Legend/O of/O Maula/LOCATION Jatt/O (/O 2022/O )/O became/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O highest/O -/O grossing/O film/O of/O all/O time/O ./O Khan/PERSON was/O born/O on/O 29/O November/O 1981/O in/O Karachi/LOCATION ,/O Sindh/LOCATION ./O [/O 3/O ]/O He/O was/O born/O to/O a/O family/O of/O Pashtun/O background/O ./O His/O father/O was/O born/O in/O Patiala/LOCATION (/O present/O -/O day/O Punjab/LOCATION ,/O India/LOCATION )/O whereas/O his/O mother/O 's/O family/O was/O native/O of/O Lucknow/LOCATION (/O present/O -/O day/O Uttar/O Pradesh/O ,/O India/LOCATION )/O ,/O who/O moved/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION after/O the/O 1947/O partition/O of/O British/O India/LOCATION ./O [/O 4/O ]/O When/O Khan/PERSON was/O young/O ,/O his/O father/O was/O in/O pharmaceutical/O sales/O ,/O which/O required/O the/O family/O to/O live/O in/O Athens/LOCATION ,/O Dubai/LOCATION ,/O Riyadh/LOCATION and/O Manchester/LOCATION during/O the/O Gulf/O War/O ./O [/O 5/O ]/O [/O 2/O ]/O His/O family/O moved/O to/O Lahore/LOCATION ,/O Punjab/LOCATION when/O he/O was/O 13/O ./O [/O 6/O ]/O He/O has/O two/O sisters/O ;/O his/O older/O sister/O ,/O Aliya/PERSON ,/O is/O an/O architect/O and/O his/O younger/O sister/O ,/O Sana/ORGANIZATION ,/O is/O a/O physician/O ./O [/O 7/O ]/O He/O currently/O lives/O in/O Lahore/LOCATION ./O [/O 8/O ]/O Khan/PERSON studied/O at/O an/O American/O school/O ,/O where/O he/O said/O he/O faced/O racial/O issues/O and/O was/O bullied/O because/O of/O his/O shy/O ,/O calm/O ,/O non-combative/O nature/O ./O [/O 9/O ]/O Khan/PERSON passed/O his/O A-levels/O at/O the/O Lahore/ORGANIZATION Grammar/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION ,/O Johar/ORGANIZATION Town/ORGANIZATION (/O LGS/O JT/O )/O ,/O and/O received/O a/O bachelor/O 's/O degree/O in/O software/O engineering/O from/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Computer/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Emerging/ORGANIZATION Sciences/ORGANIZATION (/O NUCES/O )/O in/O Lahore/LOCATION ./O [/O 10/O ]/O [/O 11/O ]/O [/O 12/O ]/O Because/O he/O could/O not/O find/O a/O job/O as/O a/O programmer/O ,/O he/O soon/O began/O acting/O ./O [/O 13/O ]/O In/O a/O Forbes/ORGANIZATION India/ORGANIZATION interview/O ,/O Khan/PERSON said/O that/O he/O had/O also/O failed/O to/O find/O a/O job/O in/O marketing/O ./O [/O 14/O ]/O By/O then/O he/O could/O play/O guitar/O ,/O bass/O and/O drums/O ,/O and/O became/O Entity/O Paradigm/O 's/O lead/O singer/O ./O [/O 15/O ]/O Khan/PERSON 's/O first/O amateur/O performance/O was/O in/O the/O title/O role/O of/O a/O play/O ,/O Spartacus/O ./O [/O 16/O ]/O Khan/O 's/O first/O television/O role/O was/O a/O bumbling/O spy/O named/O Bond/PERSON with/O his/O bandmate/O ,/O Ahmad/PERSON Ali/PERSON Butt/PERSON ,/O in/O the/O 2001/O sitcom/O Jutt/PERSON and/O Bond/PERSON ./O [/O 17/O ]/O [/O 18/O ]/O His/O debut/O film/O was/O Shoaib/PERSON Mansoor/PERSON 's/O sociodrama/O Khuda/PERSON Kay/PERSON Liye/PERSON ,/O where/O he/O played/O a/O musician/O who/O is/O brainwashed/O by/O the/O local/O maulvi/O ./O [/O 19/O ]/O Although/O the/O film/O received/O positive/O reviews/O ,/O critical/O response/O to/O Khan/PERSON 's/O performance/O was/O mixed/O ./O Taran/ORGANIZATION Adarsh/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Bollywood/ORGANIZATION Hungama/ORGANIZATION called/O it/O "/O strictly/O OK/O "/O ,/O [/O 20/O ]/O but/O The/O Economic/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION '/O film/O critic/O Gaurav/PERSON Malani/PERSON found/O him/O "/O engaged/O "/O in/O the/O role/O of/O an/O extremist/O ./O [/O 21/O ]/O Released/O in/O 2007/O ,/O the/O film/O grossed/O Rs/O ./O 250/O million/O and/O is/O one/O of/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O highest/O -/O grossing/O films/O ./O [/O 22/O ]/O Khan/O received/O the/O Lux/O Style/O Award/O for/O Best/O Actor/O –/O Film/O in/O 2008/O ,/O [/O 2/O ]/O and/O appeared/O in/O the/O TV/O series/O Dil/O Deke/O Jaenge/O ./O [/O 5/O ]/O Later/O that/O year/O ,/O in/O Anjum/PERSON Shahzad/PERSON 's/O travel/O adventure/O TV/O series/O Satrangi/O ,/O he/O played/O an/O engineer/O who/O goes/O on/O a/O road/O trip/O ./O [/O 23/O ]/O [/O 24/O ]/O [/O 17/O ]/O In/O 2010/O ,/O Khan/PERSON played/O a/O conservative/O ,/O middle/O -/O class/O boy/O in/O the/O telefilm/O Aaj/PERSON Kuch/PERSON Na/PERSON Kaho/PERSON ./O Although/O it/O received/O negative/O reviews/O ,/O Dawn/PERSON found/O Khan/PERSON "/O superbly/O convincing/O "/O and/O called/O him/O the/O film/O 's/O "/O only/O redeeming/O factor/O "/O ./O [/O 25/O ]/O That/O year/O ,/O he/O starred/O with/O Sanam/PERSON Baloch/PERSON in/O Haissam/PERSON Hussain/PERSON 's/O period/O TV/O series/O Dastaan/O ./O Based/O on/O Razia/PERSON Butt/PERSON 's/O novel/O ,/O Bano/ORGANIZATION ,/O its/O story/O (/O set/O in/O the/O 1940s/O )/O revolves/O around/O the/O separation/O of/O a/O young/O couple/O during/O the/O 1947/O partition/O ./O [/O 26/O ]/O A/O Dawn/PERSON reviewer/O wrote/O that/O Khan/PERSON and/O his/O costars/O gave/O "/O superlative/O performances/O to/O match/O Samira/PERSON Fazal/PERSON 's/O wonderful/O script/O "/O ,/O [/O 27/O ]/O and/O The/ORGANIZATION Express/ORGANIZATION Tribune/ORGANIZATION praised/O the/O lead/O pair/O 's/O onscreen/O chemistry/O ./O [/O 28/O ]/O For/O his/O performance/O ,/O Khan/PERSON won/O the/O Best/O Drama/O Actor/O award/O at/O the/O Pakistan/LOCATION Media/O Awards/O ./O [/O 29/O ]/O Haissam/PERSON Hussain/PERSON 's/O comedy/O Akbari/PERSON Asghari/PERSON ,/O a/O modern/O adaptation/O of/O Mirat/PERSON -/O ul/PERSON -/O Uroos/PERSON ,/O was/O Khan/PERSON 's/O first/O television/O series/O in/O 2011/O ;/O he/O played/O Asghar/PERSON ,/O an/O unambitious/O villager/O who/O wants/O to/O marry/O one/O of/O his/O cousins/O ./O [/O 30/O ]/O In/O an/O interview/O with/O The/O Hindu/O 's/O Anuj/PERSON Kumar/PERSON ,/O Khan/PERSON described/O his/O character/O as/O "/O completely/O oaf/O [/O ish/O ]/O "/O ./O [/O 31/O ]/O In/O Kuch/PERSON Pyar/PERSON Ka/PERSON Pagalpan/PERSON ,/O his/O third/O collaboration/O with/O Hussain/PERSON ,/O he/O starred/O with/O Sanam/PERSON Baloch/PERSON ,/O Meekal/PERSON Zulfiqar/PERSON and/O Ayesha/PERSON Khan/PERSON as/O a/O computer/O engineer/O who/O wants/O to/O take/O over/O his/O uncle/O 's/O business/O ./O [/O 32/O ]/O [/O 33/O ]/O Khan/PERSON later/O starred/O with/O Mahira/PERSON Khan/PERSON in/O Sarmad/LOCATION Khoosat/LOCATION 's/O TV/O serial/O drama/O ,/O Humsafar/O ,/O for/O which/O he/O won/O the/O Best/O Actor/O award/O at/O the/O 2012/O Lux/O Style/O Awards/O ./O [/O 34/O ]/O Humsafar/O is/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O highest/O -/O rated/O television/O serial/O ./O [/O 35/O ]/O The/O series/O and/O Khan/PERSON 's/O performance/O were/O praised/O ./O Ranika/PERSON Rajani/PERSON praised/O Humsafar/PERSON in/O The/O Indian/O Express/O ,/O calling/O it/O a/O "/O breath/O of/O fresh/O air/O "/O and/O preferring/O it/O to/O Indian/O soap/O operas/O ./O According/O to/O Rajani/PERSON ,/O the/O lead/O pair/O 's/O chemistry/O was/O the/O biggest/O factor/O in/O the/O show/O 's/O success/O ./O [/O 36/O ]/O Zee/ORGANIZATION News/ORGANIZATION critic/O Ritka/PERSON Handoo/PERSON enjoyed/O the/O protagonists/O '/O performances/O ,/O calling/O the/O Khans/O a/O "/O quite/O believable/O onscreen/O couple/O "/O ./O [/O 37/O ]/O Khan/PERSON 's/O first/O 2012/O role/O was/O Rohail/PERSON ,/O a/O Turkish/O resident/O who/O goes/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION to/O marry/O his/O cousin/O but/O instead/O marries/O her/O sister/O ,/O in/O Sarmad/LOCATION Khoosat/LOCATION 's/O Ashk/O ./O [/O 38/O ]/O [/O 39/O ]/O That/O year/O ,/O he/O played/O a/O member/O of/O an/O affluent/O family/O (/O with/O Sanam/PERSON Saeed/PERSON )/O in/O Sultana/LOCATION Siddiqui/LOCATION 's/O family/O -/O drama/O TV/O series/O Zindagi/O Gulzar/O Hai/O ./O The/O serial/O ,/O one/O of/O the/O most/O critically/O acclaimed/O Pakistani/O dramas/O ,/O also/O received/O widespread/O praise/O in/O India/LOCATION ./O [/O 40/O ]/O Dipti/PERSON Sharma/PERSON of/O The/O Indian/ORGANIZATION Express/ORGANIZATION enjoyed/O Khan/PERSON 's/O skillful/O portrayal/O ./O [/O 41/O ]/O The/O role/O earned/O him/O several/O awards/O ,/O including/O the/O Hum/O Award/O for/O Best/O Actor/O Popular/O and/O the/O Lux/O Style/O Award/O for/O Best/O Actor/O –/O Satellite/O ./O [/O 42/O ]/O [/O 43/O ]/O Khan/PERSON 's/O last/O TV/O serial/O was/O Ahson/PERSON Talish/PERSON 's/O sociodrama/O ,/O Numm/LOCATION ./O Broadcast/O in/O 2013/O ,/O Khan/PERSON played/O a/O boy/O who/O secretly/O marries/O a/O girl/O in/O London/LOCATION and/O is/O forced/O to/O marry/O another/O girl/O when/O he/O returns/O to/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O [/O 44/O ]/O Behadd/O ,/O director/O Asim/PERSON Raza/PERSON 's/O telefilm/O ,/O featured/O Khan/PERSON as/O a/O young/O divorcee/O who/O proposes/O to/O a/O widow/O who/O is/O the/O mother/O of/O a/O teenage/O girl/O ./O [/O 45/O ]/O The/O Times/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION India/ORGANIZATION noted/O that/O Khan/PERSON 's/O character/O in/O Behadd/LOCATION was/O different/O from/O those/O in/O Humsafar/LOCATION and/O Zindagi/PERSON Gulzar/PERSON Hai/PERSON ,/O calling/O it/O "/O another/O benchmark/O "/O ./O [/O 46/O ]/O His/O last/O telefilm/O was/O Anjum/PERSON Shahzad/PERSON 's/O romance/O Armaan/O (/O with/O Aamina/O Sheikh/O )/O ,/O where/O he/O played/O a/O young/O ,/O flirtatious/O boy/O ./O [/O 47/O ]/O He/O also/O co-wrote/O the/O telefilm/O 's/O screenplay/O ,/O with/O Vasay/PERSON Chaudhry/PERSON ./O [/O 48/O ]/O Khan/O was/O originally/O expected/O to/O make/O his/O debut/O in/O India/LOCATION 's/O Hindi/O film/O industry/O ,/O commonly/O known/O as/O '/O Bollywood/O '/O ,/O soon/O after/O the/O release/O of/O Khuda/PERSON Kay/PERSON Liye/PERSON but/O the/O unstable/O political/O situation/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION after/O the/O 2008/O Mumbai/LOCATION terror/O attacks/O delayed/O it/O ./O [/O 49/O ]/O He/O made/O his/O Bollywood/O debut/O in/O Shashanka/PERSON Ghosh/PERSON 's/O 2014/O comedy/O -/O drama/O ,/O Khoobsurat/LOCATION ,/O with/O Sonam/PERSON Kapoor/PERSON ./O [/O 50/O ]/O Khan/O played/O Vikram/PERSON Singh/PERSON Rathore/PERSON ,/O Kapoor/PERSON 's/O love/O interest/O and/O the/O son/O of/O her/O patient/O ./O [/O 51/O ]/O On/O Zee/ORGANIZATION News/ORGANIZATION ,/O Ritika/PERSON Handoo/PERSON praised/O his/O "/O immensely/O polished/O acting/O skills/O "/O and/O said/O that/O he/O fit/O his/O character/O very/O well/O ./O [/O 52/O ]/O Deepanjana/O Pal/O of/O Firstpost/LOCATION liked/O Gosh/PERSON 's/O decision/O to/O make/O Khan/PERSON 's/O character/O a/O sex/O object/O ,/O feeling/O that/O he/O blazed/O a/O trail/O for/O other/O male/O actors/O in/O similar/O roles/O ./O [/O 53/O ]/O The/O film/O was/O particularly/O well/O received/O in/O the/O UK/LOCATION ,/O the/O UAE/LOCATION ,/O and/O Pakistan/LOCATION because/O of/O Khan/PERSON 's/O following/O in/O those/O countries/O from/O his/O television/O work/O ./O [/O 54/O ]/O [/O 55/O ]/O He/O received/O a/O Filmfare/O Award/O for/O Best/O Male/O Debut/O for/O his/O role/O in/O the/O film/O ./O [/O 56/O ]/O Khan/PERSON made/O a/O cameo/O appearance/O in/O Asim/LOCATION Raza/LOCATION 's/O coming/O -/O of/O -/O age/O film/O ,/O Ho/PERSON Mann/PERSON Jahaan/PERSON ,/O in/O January/O 2016/O ./O [/O 57/O ]/O He/O then/O had/O a/O main/O role/O in/O Shakun/PERSON Batra/PERSON 's/O family/O drama/O ,/O Kapoor/ORGANIZATION &/O Sons/ORGANIZATION ./O The/O film/O ,/O which/O featured/O Khan/PERSON as/O part/O of/O an/O ensemble/O cast/O including/O Rishi/PERSON Kapoor/PERSON ,/O Ratna/PERSON Pathak/PERSON Shah/PERSON ,/O Rajat/PERSON Kapoor/PERSON ,/O Sidharth/PERSON Malhotra/PERSON ,/O and/O Alia/PERSON Bhatt/PERSON ,/O was/O a/O commercial/O success/O ./O The/O actor/O received/O near/O -/O unanimous/O critical/O praise/O for/O his/O portrayal/O of/O Rahul/PERSON Kapoor/PERSON ,/O a/O closeted/O homosexual/O writer/O ./O [/O 58/O ]/O [/O 59/O ]/O A/O Bollywood/O Hungama/O reviewer/O enjoyed/O Khan/PERSON 's/O performance/O ,/O saying/O that/O his/O character/O creates/O an/O emotional/O connection/O with/O the/O audience/O ,/O [/O 60/O ]/O and/O NDTV/ORGANIZATION film/O critic/O Saibal/PERSON Chaterjee/PERSON praised/O his/O self/O -/O assured/O performance/O ./O [/O 61/O ]/O Kapoor/ORGANIZATION &/O Sons/ORGANIZATION earned/O Khan/O the/O Diversity/O Award/O at/O the/O Indian/O Film/O Festival/O of/O Melbourne/LOCATION [/O 62/O ]/O [/O 63/O ]/O and/O a/O nomination/O for/O Best/O Supporting/O Actor/O at/O the/O 62nd/O Filmfare/O Awards/O ./O [/O 64/O ]/O According/O to/O the/O film/O 's/O producer/O ,/O Karan/PERSON Johar/PERSON ,/O "/O We/O went/O to/O six/O actors/O and/O after/O six/O rejections/O ,/O I/O told/O Shakun/PERSON Batra/PERSON (/O director/O )/O that/O we/O should/O drop/O the/O idea/O and/O he/O started/O developing/O another/O screenplay/O ./O Later/O ,/O in/O a/O flash/O of/O thought/O Fawad/PERSON came/O to/O my/O mind/O ./O I/O sent/O him/O the/O script/O ,/O he/O loved/O it/O and/O said/O he/O would/O do/O it/O ./O "/O [/O 65/O ]/O In/O September/O 2016/O ,/O Johar/PERSON said/O that/O Khan/PERSON 's/O wife/O pressured/O him/O to/O accept/O the/O role/O ./O [/O 66/O ]/O Later/O in/O 2016/O ,/O Khan/PERSON appeared/O in/O a/O small/O role/O with/O Ranbir/PERSON Kapoor/PERSON ,/O Anushka/PERSON Sharma/PERSON ,/O and/O Aishwarya/PERSON Rai/PERSON Bachchan/PERSON in/O Karan/PERSON Johar/PERSON 's/O romantic/O drama/O ,/O Ae/PERSON Dil/PERSON Hai/PERSON Mushkil/PERSON ./O [/O 67/O ]/O Raja/PERSON Sen/PERSON of/O Rediff.com/O found/O his/O role/O "/O far/O too/O little/O to/O justify/O the/O ridiculous/O kerfuffle/O his/O casting/O had/O caused/O "/O ,/O but/O called/O him/O the/O perfect/O choice/O for/O the/O part/O ./O [/O 68/O ]/O In/O Deccan/O Chronicle/O Subhash/PERSON K./PERSON Jha/PERSON described/O Khan/PERSON 's/O role/O as/O "/O meagre/O and/O sketchy/O "/O ./O [/O 69/O ]/O After/O the/O 2016/O Uri/O terror/O attack/O ,/O relations/O between/O India/LOCATION and/O Pakistan/LOCATION deteriorated/O and/O the/O Indian/ORGANIZATION Motion/ORGANIZATION Picture/ORGANIZATION Producers/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION (/O IMPPA/O )/O and/O the/O Film/O Producers/O Guild/O of/O India/LOCATION banned/O Pakistani/O artists/O from/O working/O in/O India/LOCATION until/O the/O situation/O normalised/O ./O [/O 70/O ]/O In/O 2022/O ,/O Khan/PERSON made/O his/O acting/O comeback/O with/O his/O Marvel/O Cinematic/O Universe/O debut/O in/O Ms./O Marvel/PERSON as/O Hassan/PERSON ,/O Kamala/PERSON Khan/PERSON //O Ms./O Marvel/PERSON 's/O great/O -/O grandfather/O ./O [/O 71/O ]/O Later/O in/O 2022/O ,/O Khan/PERSON appeared/O in/O Bilal/PERSON Lashari/PERSON 's/O Punjabi/O action/O -/O drama/O film/O ,/O The/O Legend/O of/O Maula/LOCATION Jatt/LOCATION ,/O [/O 72/O ]/O alongside/O Mahira/PERSON Khan/PERSON and/O Hamza/PERSON Ali/PERSON Abbassi/PERSON in/O which/O Fawad/PERSON played/O the/O title/O role/O originated/O by/O Sultan/PERSON Rahi/PERSON ./O For/O the/O role/O ,/O he/O gained/O considerable/O weight/O ./O [/O 73/O ]/O It/O became/O the/O highest/O -/O grossing/O Pakistani/O film/O of/O all/O time/O [/O 74/O ]/O as/O well/O as/O the/O highest/O -/O grossing/O Punjabi/O -/O language/O film/O of/O all/O time/O ./O [/O 75/O ]/O In/O 2023/O ,/O he/O appeared/O in/O Faisal/PERSON Qureshi/PERSON 's/O comedy/O film/O Money/O Back/O Guarantee/O which/O got/O mixed/O reviews/O ./O [/O 76/O ]/O In/O 2024/O ,/O Khan/PERSON appeared/O in/O Asim/PERSON Abbasi/PERSON 's/O 2024/O fantasy/O drama/O series/O Barzakh/O which/O garnered/O generally/O positive/O reviews/O from/O critics/O ./O He/O is/O expected/O to/O appear/O as/O pop/O singer/O Alamgir/PERSON in/O Sultan/PERSON Ghani/PERSON 's/O Albela/PERSON Rahi/PERSON ./O [/O 77/O ]/O He/O will/O also/O be/O seen/O with/O Mahira/PERSON Khan/PERSON in/O a/O film/O called/O Neelofer/O ./O Fawad/PERSON Khan/PERSON will/O also/O be/O seen/O in/O the/O lead/O role/O of/O renowned/O director/O and/O producer/O Haseeb/PERSON Hasan/PERSON 's/O upcoming/O film/O "/O Aan/O "/O ./O [/O 78/O ]/O [/O 79/O ]/O [/O 80/O ]/O Khan/O will/O also/O be/O seen/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION 's/O first/O Netflix/O Original/O Series/O ,/O Jo/PERSON Bachay/PERSON Hain/PERSON Sang/PERSON Samait/PERSON Lo/PERSON which/O is/O an/O official/O adaptation/O of/O Farhat/PERSON Ishtiaq/PERSON ’s/O 2013/O Urdu/O -/O language/O novel/O of/O the/O same/O name/O ./O He/O will/O star/O alongside/O Mahira/PERSON Khan/PERSON ,/O Sanam/PERSON Saeed/PERSON ,/O and/O Ahad/PERSON Raza/PERSON Mir/PERSON ./O [/O 81/O ]/O [/O 82/O ]/O Two/O rock/O bands/O ,/O Ahmed/PERSON Ali/PERSON Butt/PERSON 's/O Entity/O and/O Khan/PERSON 's/O Paradigm/O ,/O were/O active/O in/O Lahore/LOCATION between/O 1994/O and/O 2000/O ./O The/O bands/O collaborated/O on/O the/O title/O track/O of/O a/O television/O sitcom/O ,/O Jutt/PERSON and/O Bond/O (/O featuring/O Khan/PERSON and/O Ahmed/PERSON Ali/PERSON Butt/O )/O ,/O in/O the/O early/O 2000s/O ./O [/O 83/O ]/O This/O collaboration/O led/O to/O the/O bands/O '/O merger/O into/O Entity/O Paradigm/O ./O [/O 84/O ]/O The/O new/O band/O appeared/O in/O the/O 2002/O finale/O of/O Pepsi/O Battle/O of/O the/O Bands/O ,/O losing/O to/O the/O band/O Aaroh/O ./O [/O 85/O ]/O Entity/O Paradigm/O 's/O debut/O album/O ,/O Irtiqa/O ,/O was/O released/O in/O October/O 2003/O ;/O it/O received/O broad/O critical/O appreciation/O ,/O particularly/O the/O popular/O romantic/O track/O "/O Rahguzar/O "/O ./O [/O 23/O ]/O The/O band/O broke/O up/O in/O 2007/O ,/O reuniting/O in/O 2010/O to/O participate/O in/O the/O third/O season/O of/O Coke/O Studio/O (/O where/O they/O covered/O Sajjad/PERSON Ali/PERSON 's/O "/O Bolo/O Bolo/O "/O )/O ./O [/O 86/O ]/O [/O 87/O ]/O Their/O single/O ,/O "/O Shor/PERSON Macha/PERSON "/O ,/O was/O released/O that/O year/O ./O Dawn/O listed/O it/O among/O the/O year/O 's/O most/O popular/O Pakistani/O songs/O in/O the/O newspaper/O 's/O online/O poll/O ./O [/O 88/O ]/O Khan/O was/O featured/O in/O its/O video/O (/O directed/O by/O Bilal/PERSON Lashari/PERSON )/O ,/O [/O 89/O ]/O and/O said/O that/O he/O had/O played/O almost/O 250/O shows/O as/O a/O musician/O ./O [/O 90/O ]/O He/O left/O the/O band/O in/O 2012/O to/O focus/O on/O his/O acting/O career/O ./O [/O 91/O ]/O Khan/PERSON appeared/O as/O a/O judge/O on/O Pepsi/O Battle/O of/O the/O Bands/O in/O July/O 2017/O ,/O with/O Atif/PERSON Aslam/PERSON and/O Meesha/PERSON Shafi/PERSON ./O [/O 92/O ]/O He/O sang/O the/O show/O 's/O introductory/O song/O ,/O [/O 93/O ]/O and/O appeared/O in/O its/O video/O (/O released/O on/O 23/O July/O )/O with/O Aslam/PERSON and/O Shafi/PERSON ./O [/O 94/O ]/O [/O 95/O ]/O According/O to/O Vafa/PERSON Batool/PERSON of/O Pakistan/LOCATION Today/O ,/O Khan/PERSON "/O preferred/O to/O acknowledge/O the/O raw/O live/O energy/O on/O stage/O ./O "/O [/O 96/O ]/O Khan/PERSON and/O the/O other/O members/O of/O Entity/O Paradigm/O reunited/O and/O performed/O "/O Hamesha/O "/O in/O the/O show/O 's/O finale/O ./O [/O 97/O ]/O Khan/PERSON attended/O Islamic/ORGANIZATION Relief/ORGANIZATION USA/ORGANIZATION fundraisers/O in/O San/LOCATION Jose/LOCATION and/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D.C./LOCATION ,/O [/O 98/O ]/O and/O raised/O money/O for/O the/O Shukat/ORGANIZATION Khanum/ORGANIZATION Memorial/ORGANIZATION Cancer/ORGANIZATION Hospital/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Research/ORGANIZATION Centre/ORGANIZATION in/O Bahrain/LOCATION ./O [/O 99/O ]/O He/O has/O supported/O SOS/O Children/O 's/O Villages/O by/O participating/O in/O children/O 's/O carnivals/O in/O 2014/O and/O 2017/O ./O [/O 100/O ]/O [/O 101/O ]/O In/O March/O 2015/O ,/O Khan/PERSON toured/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O Canada/LOCATION and/O raised/O money/O for/O Pakistani/O charities/O ;/O [/O 102/O ]/O he/O has/O also/O raised/O money/O in/O London/LOCATION for/O charitable/O organisations/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O [/O 103/O ]/O He/O and/O his/O wife/O participated/O in/O a/O musical/O tour/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION to/O raise/O money/O for/O charitable/O organisations/O throughout/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O [/O 104/O ]/O In/O November/O 2015/O ,/O they/O officiated/O at/O the/O launch/O of/O a/O tree/O -/O planting/O event/O organised/O by/O the/O Shaukat/ORGANIZATION Khanum/ORGANIZATION Memorial/ORGANIZATION Cancer/ORGANIZATION Hospital/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Research/ORGANIZATION Centre/ORGANIZATION in/O Peshawar/LOCATION ./O [/O 4/O ]/O Khan/PERSON appeared/O in/O Ali/PERSON Zafar/PERSON 's/O music/O video/O ,/O "/O Urainge/O "/O ,/O which/O was/O made/O as/O a/O tribute/O to/O the/O victims/O of/O the/O 2014/O Peshawar/LOCATION school/O attack/O ./O [/O 105/O ]/O He/O is/O the/O Italian/O brand/O Giovanni/PERSON 's/O brand/O ambassador/O in/O Pakistan/LOCATION ./O [/O 106/O ]/O Khan/O is/O also/O the/O Pakistani/O brand/O ambassador/O for/O the/O Suzuki/ORGANIZATION Vitara/ORGANIZATION ,/O [/O 107/O ]/O Pepsi/ORGANIZATION ,/O [/O 108/O ]/O Oye/PERSON Hoye/PERSON ,/O [/O 109/O ]/O Tapal/O Tea/O ,/O [/O 110/O ]/O Zameen.com/O ,/O [/O 111/O ]/O Servis/O Shoes/O ,/O Samsung/ORGANIZATION ,/O Telenor/ORGANIZATION ,/O Jazz/O ,/O Warid/LOCATION ,/O LUX/ORGANIZATION ,/O Tarang/ORGANIZATION ,/O Aquafina/O ,/O Clear/O ,/O Olper/PERSON 's/O ,/O Lays/O ,/O Bold/O ,/O Nestle/ORGANIZATION ,/O QMobile/O and/O TUC/ORGANIZATION biscuits/O ./O [/O 112/O ]/O He/O has/O been/O an/O ambassador/O for/O the/O Pakistan/ORGANIZATION Super/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION 's/O Islamabad/ORGANIZATION United/ORGANIZATION cricket/O team/O since/O January/O 2016/O ./O [/O 113/O ]/O [/O 114/O ]/O Khan/O modeled/O for/O fashion/O designer/O Munib/PERSON Nawaz/PERSON in/O 2010/O ,/O [/O 115/O ]/O Umar/PERSON Sayeed/PERSON in/O 2012/O ,/O [/O 116/O ]/O and/O for/O the/O Republic/O by/O Omar/PERSON Farooq/PERSON in/O 2015/O ./O [/O 117/O ]/O Khan/O is/O one/O of/O the/O highest/O -/O paid/O actors/O in/O the/O Pakistani/O film/O industry/O ./O [/O 118/O ]/O [/O 119/O ]/O According/O to/O director/O and/O producer/O Abdullah/PERSON Kadwani/PERSON ,/O "/O Fawad/PERSON is/O the/O closest/O actor/O to/O Waheed/PERSON Murad/PERSON ./O "/O [/O 47/O ]/O Soon/O after/O the/O release/O of/O Khoobsurat/LOCATION ,/O The/O Indian/ORGANIZATION Express/ORGANIZATION 's/O Mimansa/PERSON Shekhar/PERSON wrote/O that/O the/O actor/O redefined/O the/O Bollywood/O actor/O with/O charm/O ,/O replacing/O "/O stereotype/O body/O builders/O with/O six/O packs/O "/O ./O [/O 120/O ]/O After/O the/O success/O of/O Kapoor/ORGANIZATION &/O Sons/ORGANIZATION ,/O Nirmalya/ORGANIZATION Dutta/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Daily/ORGANIZATION News/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Analysis/ORGANIZATION called/O Khan/PERSON 's/O portrayal/O of/O a/O gay/O male/O "/O a/O big/O leap/O forward/O for/O India/LOCATION 's/O LGBT/O movement/O "/O ;/O in/O India/LOCATION ,/O where/O homosexuality/O was/O illegal/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O "/O Khan/PERSON had/O the/O guts/O and/O gumption/O to/O play/O this/O seminal/O role/O ./O "/O [/O 121/O ]/O In/O August/O 2016/O ,/O Ranbir/PERSON Kapoor/PERSON said/O that/O Khan/PERSON opened/O a/O door/O by/O playing/O a/O gay/O man/O and/O he/O was/O now/O comfortable/O playing/O such/O a/O role/O ./O [/O 122/O ]/O Khan/O is/O described/O by/O South/O Asian/O media/O as/O one/O of/O its/O most/O attractive/O men/O ,/O [/O 123/O ]/O and/O he/O was/O named/O the/O Most/O Beautiful/O Man/O at/O the/O 2015/O Vogue/O Beauty/O Awards/O ./O [/O 124/O ]/O He/O was/O ranked/O third/O in/O the/O Times/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION India/ORGANIZATION 's/O 50/O Most/O Desirable/O Men/O poll/O in/O 2014/O [/O 125/O ]/O and/O 2015/O ,/O [/O 126/O ]/O and/O was/O fifth/O in/O 2016/O ./O [/O 127/O ]/O In/O November/O 2014/O ,/O Khan/PERSON received/O the/O Fresh/O Face/O of/O the/O Year/O Award/O at/O the/O Hello/O !/O Hall/O of/O Fame/O Awards/O in/O India/LOCATION ./O [/O 128/O ]/O The/O British/O magazine/O Eastern/O Eye/O ranked/O Khan/PERSON seventh/O in/O 2014/O [/O 129/O ]/O and/O sixth/O from/O 2015/O to/O 2018/O [/O 130/O ]/O third/O [/O 131/O ]/O and/O sixth/O [/O 132/O ]/O on/O its/O annual/O list/O of/O sexiest/O Asian/O men/O ./O For/O his/O style/O and/O fashion/O ,/O he/O received/O the/O Crush/O of/O the/O Year/O Award/O at/O the/O Grazia/O Young/O Fashion/O Awards/O ./O [/O 133/O ]/O TC/ORGANIZATION Candler/ORGANIZATION ,/O an/O independent/O critics/O list/O ,/O nominated/O Khan/PERSON as/O one/O of/O the/O 100/O Most/O Handsome/O Faces/O of/O 2017/O ./O [/O 134/O ]/O He/O was/O nominated/O for/O the/O International/O Pakistan/O Prestige/O Award/O for/O Style/O Icon/O of/O the/O Year/O in/O September/O 2017/O [/O 135/O ]/O (/O which/O went/O to/O Hamza/PERSON Ali/PERSON Abbasi/PERSON )/O ./O [/O 136/O ]/O The/O Herald/ORGANIZATION named/O Khan/O one/O of/O its/O 10/O People/O of/O 2016/O ./O [/O 137/O ]/O He/O was/O ranked/O the/O fifth/O -/O most/O -/O popular/O Bollywood/O actor/O of/O November/O 2014/O ,/O [/O 138/O ]/O and/O was/O called/O the/O most/O popular/O Bollywood/O actor/O in/O March/O 2016/O by/O Times/ORGANIZATION Celebex/ORGANIZATION ./O [/O 139/O ]/O MenXP/O ranked/O Khan/PERSON 37th/O on/O its/O Most/O Popular/O Bollywood/O celebrities/O of/O 2014/O list/O ./O [/O 140/O ]/O He/O was/O the/O first/O Pakistani/O to/O appear/O on/O the/O cover/O of/O Filmfare/O magazine/O ,/O in/O September/O 2014/O ,/O [/O 141/O ]/O and/O again/O appeared/O on/O its/O cover/O in/O October/O 2015/O [/O 142/O ]/O and/O March/O 2016/O ./O [/O 143/O ]/O Hi/O !/O Blizt/O magazine/O featured/O Khan/PERSON on/O its/O cover/O in/O 2016/O ./O [/O 144/O ]/O He/O received/O the/O Best/O Male/O Debut/O Award/O at/O the/O IBNlive/O Movie/O Awards/O ,/O with/O 48.54/O per/O cent/O of/O the/O vote/O ./O [/O 145/O ]/O Khan/PERSON married/O Sadaf/PERSON Khan/PERSON (/O nee/PERSON Ahmad/PERSON )/O in/O 2005/O after/O a/O seven/O -/O year/O courtship/O ./O [/O 146/O ]/O [/O 147/O ]/O They/O have/O three/O children/O ./O [/O 148/O ]/O [/O failed/O verification/O ]/O [/O 149/O ]/O Khan/PERSON and/O his/O wife/O founded/O Silk/O by/O Fawad/PERSON Khan/PERSON ,/O a/O clothing/O line/O ,/O [/O 150/O ]/O whose/O debut/O collection/O was/O launched/O in/O August/O 2012/O in/O Lahore/LOCATION ./O [/O 151/O ]/O He/O was/O diagnosed/O with/O Type/O 1/O diabetes/O at/O age/O 17/O ,/O after/O an/O accident/O which/O damaged/O his/O pancreas/O ./O [/O 152/O ]/O The/O accident/O occurred/O behind/O a/O swimming/O pool/O ,/O where/O Khan/PERSON was/O scratched/O and/O jumped/O into/O untreated/O water/O ./O He/O later/O realized/O he/O had/O the/O disease/O when/O he/O lost/O 10/O kilograms/O (/O 22/O lb/O )/O ./O [/O 153/O ]/O Khan/PERSON performed/O Hajj/O ,/O the/O annual/O pilgrimage/O of/O Muslims/O to/O Makkah/LOCATION ,/O along/O with/O his/O family/O in/O 2018/O and/O was/O therein/O invited/O to/O the/O Annual/O Hajj/O Lunch/O by/O King/O Salman/PERSON and/O Crown/O Prince/O Mohammed/PERSON bin/PERSON Salman/PERSON of/O Saudi/LOCATION Arabia/LOCATION ./O [/O 154/O ]/O